<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ossia score</title>
    <description>Open software system for interactive applications
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 16:16:27 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 16:16:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Control DMX lighting devices with i-score</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For now, i-score can send and receive only OSC or MIDI messages. But if you would like to use i-score to control lighting devices, there is a nice framework that can be used to translate OSC messages to Artnet, Sacn on a local network. It’s called OLA for Open Lighting Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ola can handle a lot of lighting protocols such as described on this page. You can download a namespace for OLA here, and a conf file for OSC plugin of OLA here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/control-dmx/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/control-dmx/</guid>
        
        
        <category>To check</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version 0.3 development sprint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the i-score core developers are currently running a development sprint at GMEA – Centre National de Création Musicale d’Albi-Tarn for the OSSIA (Open Scenario System for Interactive Application) project. They have been doing a great job putting together a solid basis as i-score moves toward version 0.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s work has been focusing on both i-score’s underlying architecture as well as its user interface and general workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Théo De La Hogue and Clément Bossut have been refining i-score’s engine’s API. As part of the OSSIA project, the Score C++ library should be easily implemented in other environments so that users are free to write a scenario in a dedicated application such as i-score while executing it thru a Max external or some distributed Raspberry devices for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side, Jean-Michaël Celerier and Nicolas Vuaille have been working on the graphical interface. i-score 0.3 and above will have a much improved workflow. The device explorer will be much more powerfull, by providing support for dynamic namespaces, filtering options, namespaces presets and more… This will make it much easier to deal with remote control of applications that have a huge namespace (i.e. device’s parameter architecture).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MaquetteI-score0.3New-600x308.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general timeline workflow has also been considerably refined. Based on an event-centered approach, i-score will allow to interleave events and processes and to further merge timeline and cue-based approaches. Thanks to work done on Score API, a plugin system will make it possible to add interpolation and automations between events as of version 0.2, but also to add other processes such as mappings, sub-scenarios, loops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of other features are also on the workbench. So stay tuned for upcoming sneak peeks on i-score next big iteration !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/v0_3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/v0_3/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User experience workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding: 0;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/83989990&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/83989990&quot;&gt;Le chant du filament&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user24205756&quot;&gt;NICOLAS VILLENAVE&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following November’s last development sprint, GMEA – Centre National de Création Musicale d’Albi-Tarn invited a bunch of i-score users as part of the OSSIA project. This workshop focussed on users experiments with i-score version 0.2.x and feedbacks regarding i-score 0.3 features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to i-score core developers, were welcomed Pascal Baltazar who coordinates i-score development and extensively used i-score for the Nocturnes project led by Les Baltazars, Mathieu Chamagne who experiments i-score for interactive sound and visual installation as well as doing researches for spatial scenarios representations, Julien Rabin who is in charged of research and development at GMEA as well as working on i-score documentation, Renaud Rubiano who experiments i-score for live art productions and for his in progress installation Mobiles and Antoine Villeret who recently used i-score for Mylène Benoît’s project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with LaBRI and Grame – Centre National de Création Musicale, GMEA also invited Nicolas Villenave to experiment i-score for his project Le chant du filament. Together with Max Bruckert, Clément Bossut et Jaime Chao, Le chant du filament’s team made its Max-based software interoperable in order to make the various light processes controlled by i-score.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/ux-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/ux-workshop/</guid>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
